Siinn Che

Address: 191 W. Woodruff Ave. Columbus, OH, 43210 • Phone: 510-967-5152 • Email: siinn.che@gmail.com

Blog: http://siinn.github.io • Github: github.com/siinn • Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/siinn-che

SUMMARY

Ph.D. student with extensive experience in **data analysis** with large experiment data at **CERN**. Proficient in data modeling, manipulation, and visualization with 5 years of experience in **Python** and C++. Strong background in **mathematics** and **statistics** from academic training. Enjoys working with others in a **collaborative** environment. Highly motivated to make a positive impact in **data science** with quantitative skills, knowledge and training.

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

CERN (The European Organization for Nuclear Research)

Geneva, Switzerland, 2013 - 2018

Graduate Researcher

- Data Analysis: Processed and analyzed large data (~200 TB) from ATLAS experiment with reduction rate < 5% in search for new physics.
- Data Mining: Developed a data mining algorithm to improve the efficiency of extracting rare physics data from 20% to over 90%.
- Modeling: Designed Monte Carlo simulation of complex physics processes using random sampling and statistical modeling.
- Visualization: Developed and implemented a visualization tool for experiment data at the Ohio State using Python Web App

LBNL (Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory)

Berkeley, CA 2009 - 2012

Research Associate

Modeling: Designed a simulation of complex molecular dynamics experiment using MATLAB

EDUCATION

Ph.D.	Experimental Particle Physics, The Ohio State University	2014 - 2017
	"Search for Long-lived Neutral Massive Particle with Displaced dilepton Resonance at the LHC"	
M.S.	Experimental Particle Physics, The Ohio State University	2012 - 2014
	"Higgs Boson as a Tool for Discovery at the LHC"	
B.A.	Mathematics & Physics, University of California, Berkeley	2007 - 2011
	Academic Achievement Scholarship Award, 2008, Linear Algebra (A+), Computational Physics (A)	

INDEPENDENT PROJECTS

End-to-End Project:	NYC Rent Prediction: Regression models are built to predict apartment rent in NYC using RandomForest and
	GradientBoosting regressors using data collected by web scrapping . Two regression models are compared using learning
	curves and cross-validation metrics.
Selected Kaggle Project	Recognizing hand-written digits: Analyzed and classified images of hand-written digits from MNIST dataset using Principal
	component analysis (PCA) and unsupervised learning (K-Mean clustering).
In-course Projects	Natural language processing, Recommender system, SVM, Geographical Plotting.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Data science	Python (pandas, numpy, scikit-learn, matplotlib, seaborn), SQL.
Machine Learning	Scikit-learn (model selection, regression, classification, clustering, PDA).
Research	C++, ROOT statistics package, Distributed computing.
Development Environment	UNIX (bash, ssh), svn, Github , LaTex, Jupyter notebook.